WEB DEVELOPER

Web Developer with over 17 years of web development experience (UI/UX, websites, web ads, SEO) and 10 years of web project management experience. An MFA in Creative Writing provides a unique combination of technological expertise and stellar communication skills. Passionate about creating logical and intuitive interfaces on the web regardless of the device used.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• Front End Engineer

October 2013 – Present Spotify

- Work on a team that manages Spotify Radio on all platforms
- O Developing apps for the Spotify Desktop, Web, and Android Clients

• Lead Front End Engineer

February 2013 – October 2013 Zeebox (zeebox.com) U.S.

- o Code HTML 5 Games, Responsive Websites, and other Javascript Applications
- Manage a group of mid-level developers
- Advise on best web practices, code management and versioning, cross-browser/cross-device compatibility, and browser memory management and optimization.

• Senior Web Developer

February 2007 – February 2013

The City University of New York (CUNY) Office of Communications and Marketing

- o Team Leader of Central Office web team (developers, content editors, server admins)
- Develop for and maintain cuny.edu (10 million + page-views/month): XSL, XML, Javascript, PHP, MySQL, HTML 5, CSS3
- Manage university web projects: CUNY School of Law, CUNY School of Public Health, New Community College.

Freelance Web Developer/Designer

October 2006 – Present

- o Over 20 clients in multiple industries.
- o Designed and Built Websites using Wordpress, Joomla, Drupal, Lenya.

Web Developer

October 2005 – May 2007 Sarah Lawrence College

- o Manager of college web projects: content editing, site development, information architecture, client
- Developer: Online student applications and web tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, JSP.

Web Developer

June 1997 – September 1999 UCLA Medical School

o Developer and Departmental Liaison: web content editing, development, and design.

LANGUAGES

Javascript, Java, PHP, XSTL, Shell Scripting, MySQL, HTML, CSS

FRAMEWORKS & APPLICATIONS

NodeJS, React, Redux, Angular, Backbone, Grunt, Gulp, SOAP, AJAX, Wordpress, Drupal, Joomla, Lenya, Hippo, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Suite, Github, SVN

SKILLS

SEO, semantic markup, responsive design, accessibility standards, web performance optimization

EDUCATION AND HONORS

B.A. in Literature 2003
 University of California Santa Barbara
 College of Creative Studies (www.ccs.ucsb.edu)

• M.F.A. in Creative Writing: Poetry May 2007 Sarah Lawrence College (www.slc.edu)

FREELANCE WEB PROJECTS

www.cunyprep.org - www.changentcoaching.com - www.marinacooks.com - www.storyscapejournal.com - www.sethfenton.com - www.louderarts.com - www.citybankantiques.com - www.piquelearning.com - www.academyofcreativeeducation.com - www.millermenthelaw.com - www.melanierome.com - www.oralmalodor.com - www.unitednationsoffood.com - www.melanierome.com - www.cameronmcpherson.com